Ah...
Mmm.
I am legion.
I am Satan.
I am foulmouthed behemoth.
You doubt me?
You will find out
soon enough.
You mock me?!
I can possess anyone I choose.
Ah.
Anyone! Anything!
I do not believe you.
I don't believe you could even
possess this pig.
Can you do it?
You have the power.
Could you possess the pig?
Yes, I can.
Come on, Satan.
- Watch me!
- Possess the pig.
Show me you are
the Prince of Darkness.
Show to me your power!
Have you done it?
You can sleep now, my son.
The demon has gone.
God is with you.
♪ Oh, the heads that turn ♪
♪ Make my back burn ♪
♪ And those heads that turn ♪
♪ Make my back,
make my back burn ♪
Amy.
We're not in America anymore.
You can't dress like that.
Why?
Because there's going to be
construction workers
everywhere.
How you doing back there?
So, we left everything
for this?
Amy, please.
Don't start.
Yeah, 'cause you know
exactly what I'm gonna say.
Yes, and I don't want
to hear it.
What do you think?
Pretty cool, huh?
Yeah, I know.
Cuckoo.
Gabriele.
That is a question
of theology.
No shit.
Perhaps it was his mercy
that stayed
Saint Michael's sword.
The only thing
that arrests God's love
is a person's freedom
to choose.
But God cannot be God
unless he allows
for this choice,
even for the damned.
Saint Michael, he knows this.
We will all be judged.
We will all be judged
by how much we love.
Hmm.
Do not worry, Gabriele.
I will defend you.
Defend me?
Hmm.
My faith does not
require defense.
Wow.
What do you think, guys?
Cozy.
Oh, come on. Give it a chance.
This is awesome.
Carlos, hi!
So nice to put a face
to the voice.
Um, Padre...
Father Esquibel, uh...
Pleasure to meet you,
Ms. Vasquez.
Uh, Julia, please.
Carlos was giving me a tour.
Hmm.
Oh, great.
I just wanted to stop by
and welcome you and your family
to the diocese.
I'm-I'm sorry.
Oh, no, no, please.
Go for it.
I'm glad to see
you made it safe.
All right,
go find your room, twerp.
Hey, can I get one of those?
Thank you.
It's a wonderful
thing you're doing,
restoring the abbey.
We are being very respectful
of the existing architecture.
This, this has actually been
in my husband's family
for generations,
and we just inherited it.
Is Mr. Vasquez here or...
Oh, uh, he passed, actually,
about a year ago.
I'm sorry for your loss.
It's okay.
If you need anything, please,
hmm? Don't hesitate.
Okay.
I will remember him
in my prayers.
Oh, that's very kind of you.
Thank you.
It was nice to meet you.
Okay, Carlos, talk to me.
What's up?
Where are we at?
The basement excavation
is very complicated.
So, more expensive then,
you mean, right?
- I'm afraid so.
- All right.
I'll take another look
at the plans
if you can just show me
what the basement looks like.
Maybe I can wire some...
Amy!
Get off of there
before you break your neck.
Is that a cigarette?
Put that out right now, please.
Fine.
No! Oh, my God.
Cute.
Get out of my room.
♪ Beautiful girl,
lovely dress ♪
♪ Where she is now,
I can only guess ♪
♪ Cause it's gone daddy gone,
the love is gone ♪
♪ Yeah, it's gone daddy gone ♪
♪ The love is gone ♪
♪ The love is gone... ♪
Hey, have you seen
your brother?
Amy.
Look, I really can't handle
the silent treatment
from both my kids.
I know you don't want
to be here.
Yeah, no shit.
Amy... please.
I need your help.
This abbey is the only thing
your dad left us.
We don't have an income
anymore.
Once we fix it up and sell it,
we'll go home. Okay?
Maybe if you could just
at least watch your brother.
Maybe try and get him
to talk.
How? He hasn't spoken
in almost a year.
Can you try for me?
So, you want me to be
a mother for you?
Please just keep an eye
on your brother. Okay?
♪ Whoa, whoa ♪
♪ It's a dirty job,
but someone's gotta do it ♪
♪ We care a lot. ♪
Father Amorth,
caffè latte?
Sugar?
This is
a formal hearing.
And as agreed, proceedings
will be undertaken in English.
On the night of June 4th
in the town of Tropea,
you performed an exorcism
without the approval
of the Reggio Calabria bishop.
In English, Father Amorth.
That was not an exorcism.
From Father Johnny's
description,
what occurred
in Reggio Calabria
sounded exactly like
an exorcism,
complete with animal sacrifice
no less.
The boy was maladjusted.
A temporary mental illness.
I use, uh,
primitive psychology.
The power of suggestion.
You addressed the subject
as Satan,
and called for him
to display his power.
Do you deny this?
No.
That's what I did.
And why would you do that?
Exorcism is my job,
but the vast majority of
the cases to which I'm assigned
do not require an exorcism.
They just need, uh,
a little conversation,
a little understanding,
and sometimes...
a little theater.
Cardinal Sullivan,
in my observation,
98% of the cases that
are assigned to Father Amorth
are then further recommended
by him
to doctors and psychiatrists.
And the other two percent?
Ah, the other two percent. Hmm.
This is something that has
confounded all of science
and all of medicine
for a very long time.
I call it...
evil.
Your Eminence, with hundreds
of successful exorcisms,
Father Amorth has been
very effective in...
One moment,
Bishop Lumumba.
You do raise
an interesting point, Amorth.
You are not a doctor,
but these practices of yours
could have damaging effects
on these people.
You are right.
I am not a doctor.
I am not a psychologist.
But I am a theologian,
I am a lawyer,
I am a journalist,
and I am a practical man.
I was also a partisan
in the war,
so I know a firing squad
when I see one.
So, what is this about?
The Congregation
for the Doctrine of the Faith
has recommended
to this panel
that the position of Chief
Exorcist be formally vacated.
So, what you are saying is
that evil does not exist?
The Church is under
constant pressure
to sharpen her relevance.
It's time we move past
these outdated beliefs.
Explain to me, please,
Your Eminence.
If evil does not exist,
what then is the role
of the Church?
I think we all
have to be careful
of the Congregation
for the Doctrine of the Faith.
Sounds to me like they want us
all out of a job.
Mm.
We have more questions for you,
Father Amorth.
How is it
that I am suddenly worthy
of the time and attention
of all you powerful men?
I ask you again,
what is this about?
Due process, Father.
So, this is not about
the dead girl, Rosaria Velendez,
that I write about
in "La Madre di Dio" magazine?
What is your due diligence
and process on this?
Please, Cardinal.
I warn you! I warn you!
Father Amorth,
show respect to your superiors.
I do!
I am the Chief Exorcist
of the Vatican.
My position was appointed
by my bishop.
My diocese is Rome.
My local bishop is the Pope.
If you have a problem with me,
you talk to my boss.
Okay?
The Pope is infirm.
Father Amorth,
you have not been dismissed!
Cuckoo!
Father Amorth!
Hello?
Anyone there?
They hit a gas deposit.
We can't continue
working here.
I'm pulling my team
from this place.
Wait.
Henry?
Henry!
Mom!
Oh, my God!
Henry!
What is happening?
I don't know.
He was like this
when I came in.
Henry?
Henry, it's Mommy.
Talk to me.
Henry.
Oh, my God.
Mommy.
He's talking.
Hen-Henry.
Mommy.
You're all going to die.
Henry! What are you doing?!
Henry! Henry!
Henry!
X-rays, blood tests,
even the spinal tap
and MRI show no results
of ischemia or hematoma.
What does that mean?
All of his, uh, vitals
and brain functions
seem to be normal.
Wait, normal? What do you mean?
He was convulsing.
Has he been through
any trauma recently?
Um...
yeah, uh, his dad died
about a year ago.
And how did he react?
Uh, he hasn't spoken since.
Wha... Psychosis?
No, that's not possible.
He's just a little boy.
Ma'am, uh, there is nothing
that we can do now.
But he can recommend
a good psychiatrist.
What is this?
If your son continues
trying to hurt himself,
you can administer him
this sedative.
No.
Mom.
I'm so sorry.
Baby.
Oh, my God.
Oh.
No, I don't think
you understand.
But this is an emergency,
please.
No, I, I need to talk
to someone
at the consulate
who can help me.
I need a-a specialist.
Okay.
Yes, please.
Baby.
Oh.
Hey.
My love, come here.
Fuck this.
Henry, no.
Henry, stop!
Your baby's hungry,
you fat cow.
What? What are you saying?
You never breastfed me, Mommy.
- What?
- What the fuck?
Ow.
What the fuck
is that?
Bring me the priest.
Can you help us?
Yes.
I'm here to help, Julia.
Okay.
Wrong fucking priest!
There's a case
that needs your attention.
A boy in Spain.
Something about it
disturbs me greatly.
This boy's possession
is progressing very fast.
The incident took place
in hallowed ground,
San Sebastian Abbey in Castile.
This place has given the Church
problems before.
I sense a great evil
coming from there.
Something dark that only you
can help solve.
I have requested
the abbey's records
be brought to you
in the library.
Look into it.
I will continue investigating
while you're on your journey.
"Our sins...
will seek us out."
Gabriele, go to Spain,
and help this child.
But be careful,
this demon sounds dangerous.
Hello?
Ah.
Wait. Father Amorth?
Sì.
Ah.
I-I didn't expect them
to send you.
You know me?
Yes.
I have read all the articles.
And the books?
No, no.
No, not the books.
The books are good.
I-I will read...
Okay.
I'll just get my bag.
You, uh...
Whiskey?
No, no, no, no. Thank you.
Yeah, this sore throat.
Uh, the... dust.
Julia, we have been
extremely lucky.
The Church sent someone.
An expert in these matters.
Gabriele, please come in.
I have come from Roma.
I'm sorry that you came
all this way,
but I don't even know why the
Church is interested in this.
I just want my son to be well.
Tell me something,
have the doctors given you
any answers?
Any comfort?
If you would at least...
just let me see your son.
I can give you my opinion,
and you can do with it
what you will.
It's worth a shot.
Okay. He's upstairs.
Hello, my friend.
Henry?
Are you awake?
Your prayers are worthless here.
Who are you?
Your worst fear.
I am your demise.
Why are you possessing
this boy?
'Cause it feels so good
to ruin such innocent flesh.
But I prefer the challenge
of an exorcist's soul.
You only serve
to diminish yourself.
Don't lecture me, priest.
What is your purpose?
I'm here for you.
Then you must know my name.
I know your soul
and every shameless sin.
Tell me one of my sins.
You cannot.
Because my sins
have been absolved
by the one true master,
the Lord Jesus Christ.
Do not speak of him.
Are you afraid of him?
Are you afraid of Jesus Christ?
Whatever you do,
you only do
because God allows it.
Did he allow that?
This is
just the beginning.
You don't know
who you're dealing with.
Then tell me.
Tell me your name.
Unless you are too afraid.
I'm not some stupid fuck
you convince to get into a pig.
So you won't
tell me your name.
My name is blasphemy.
My name is nightmare.
Huh.
My nightmare...
is France winning
the World Cup.
You prideful fool.
You can't hide behind
your jokes forever...
Gabriele.
I know your nightmares, too.
Beware, your sins
will seek you out.
I'll be waiting for you,
Gabe.
Did you mention my name
to anyone in this house?
Maybe. I'm not sure.
This demon,
it says things
that it could not know.
So it's, it's real?
What do you know
about demons?
O-Only the basics,
that they are fallen angels.
One serves the other
in a hierarchy.
The higher the demon,
the more access it can have.
So why is it possessing
the boy?
This is a very good question.
I'm going to talk
to the mother.
I need to work out why
this demon has chosen Henry.
What I am about to say
may be difficult.
Confronting.
Your son is under the influence
of a very powerful demon.
Removing the boy from this place
could be fatal.
I say to you now the only way
your son comes back to you
is through faith.
Mrs. Vasquez,
did anything happen
to Henry?
He was in the car accident
that killed his father.
He saw his father impaled.
That memory, that's his demon.
I give you my word,
I will not walk away from you
or your son.
Trauma, such as you describe,
can be a gateway for the devil.
Suffering can make a soul
desperate for connection.
It can make the innocent
more vulnerable.
You must have loved
your husband very much.
You have no idea.
He was your
soul connection, sì?
He was everything.
And you have
two beautiful children.
A mother's love is the closest
thing we know to God's love.
Tell me, Julia...
have you ever believed?
Uh, when I was a little girl,
I used to think that
my guardian angel
walked me to school.
You should pray
to that guardian angel.
♪ 'Cause I'm stranded
on my own ♪
♪ Stranded far from home... ♪
Henry?
Amy.
I'm in Hell.
Amy, honey, it's Dad.
You have to listen, okay?
Daddy?
You're all going to die.
Mom! Mom, it was Daddy.
It was Dad.
Amy.
I heard Dad's voice.
I heard his voice
on the phone.
He said that we're all
gonna die.
What?
He said
that we were all gonna die.
Oh, my God.
What do we do?
Coffee.
Uh, the demons, they grow
more strong in the night.
I'm going to need
my energy.
But you should try
to get some rest.
Amen.
How long will this take?
That is hard to say.
Hours.
Days, maybe.
This demon
is very strong.
The boy won't last long.
What we need to do
is to find out its name
in order to exorcise it.
That is the only way
we can save the boy.
How do we do that?
With prayer.
Constant prayer.
The demons,
they are self-preserving.
They do not understand
suffering.
Eventually,
he will give himself up
because he cannot stand
the pain of the prayer.
You understand me?
Yes.
Good. Good.
Now, you must confess
your sins.
Now?
The demon can smell your sins
if they are not absolved. Come.
We begin.
Forgive me, Father,
for I have sinned.
It has been, uh... eight months
since my last confession...
Did you just say eight months
since your last confession?
Yes.
I...
Okay, we just have
to get this done.
Y-You are a man of God,
simple enough.
Sì?
Yes.
And you are very, very sorry
for all of your sins.
Sì?
Yes.
Okay.
May Almighty God
have mercy on you
and having forgiven your sins,
lead you to eternal peace.
Amen.
What rites of the exorcism
do you know?
Uh... none.
None?
It has never come up.
What prayer do you know that
you could say over and over,
even under pressure?
The Hail Mary.
But if it is
under pressure,
I would prefer to say it
in Spanish.
That's fine.
Your job is to pray.
Do not engage
with the demon.
Do not respond to anything
it says or does.
Your job is to be
implacabile.
Relentless. Okay?
Good boy.
Do you know any jokes?
Uh, no.
You should learn some.
The devil does not like jokes.
Bring the box.
I see you've brought
your friend.
He looks a little scared, Gabe.
Mind if I call you Gabe, Gabe?
Readying for battle?
You ran out on me
last time,
like the coward you are,
soldier boy.
Not very becoming
of the Chief Exorcist.
Who do you want
to be vanquished by today,
Jesus or his mother?
Fuck the Holy Mother.
Are we going to talk all night,
or do you want to battle?
Know what I'm going to do
to you, Gabriele?
I'm going to fuck you.
You'll sense yourself coming,
and you'll hate yourself
for the release you feel
when I fuck you.
Now we pray.
I command you, unclean spirit,
whoever you are,
along with all of your minions
now attacking this servant
of God, Henry,
by the mysteries
of the incarnation...
Fuck you and your incarnations.
...passion, resurrection,
and ascension
of our Lord Jesus Christ,
by the descent
of the Holy Spirit,
by the coming of our Lord
for judgment,
that you tell me
by some sign your name
and the day and hour
of your departure.
Tomás, pray. Pray.
I command you, moreover,
to obey me to the letter,
I who am a minister of God
despite my unworthiness...
Rosaria?
Your sins will seek you out.
My sins have been forgiven.
But you can't forgive yourself,
can you, Father?
Not for me,
the girl you let die.
Why did you do nothing?
Why didn't you believe me?
Now I am in Hell!
Deceiver.
Her soul rests in peace.
My soul rots in Hell!
How touching.
Is that all you got?
And how about you,
panty sniffer?
You didn't tell him,
did you?
About your little whore?
Your little sweet treat,
Adella.
After you stood before
your congregation
like you're better than them,
when you're fucking
their daughters.
Maybe you aren't so sorry
about that sin, hmm?
Shut up.
Tomás. Tomás.
Do not speak to it.
Pray.
Run away.
You don't want
to be here, Tomás.
You'd rather be fucking
that little whore.
Tomás! Tomás! No, no, no!
That's what it wants.
You've been played, Amorth.
You took the bait.
And I'll destroy you.
Your Holy Church will crumble
from the inside.
She was
the love of my life.
A promise was made.
She wanted me to leave
the priesthood for her...
...but I had no intention
of doing that.
So I just told her
what she wanted.
My love for God...
it outweighed my love for her.
Are you sorry for your sins?
Yes.
May Almighty God
show you mercy.
And having forgiven
your sins,
may he lead you
to eternal life.
Amen.
Who is... Rosaria?
She is a girl
that I should've helped.
The demon is using her memory
to deceive me.
How does it know these things?
It can sense our guilt,
and it uses it against us
as a distraction.
That boy, he does not have long
before he expires.
We need to find out
the name of this demon.
Knowing its name,
it weakens them.
I didn't mean to hurt him.
I understand.
See here.
I have marked this page
for you.
Learn that.
But i-it is in Latin.
Close enough to Spanish.
Prayer has more power
in Latin.
"You have taken the bait."
What?
What it said to me.
"You have taken the bait,
Amorth."
This is not about the boy.
It has a bigger plan.
I need to check something
I saw in the garden.
Go. Take this.
Be outside his door.
He is still in danger.
We must protect him
at all cost.
Do whatever you have to.
The seal of the Vatican.
This place has given
the Church problems before.
Help me.
Henry?
No one's getting out
of here alive.
No one.
Let's see what secrets
you are hiding.
What happened?
Go!
Help me!
Amorth!
Help me! Help!
Amy!
Amy! Amy!
Amy. Amy. Oh, my God. Oh, Amy.
It's one of her nails.
Tomás,
take them to the chapel.
Everything is redacted.
"Our sins will seek us out."
Are you okay?
Yes.
You don't
get to stay handsome
in this business
for too long.
Please, hmm? Don't.
I once have a demon try to put
a crucifix into my eyeball.
You're always talking
and talking. Enough.
Please.
Shh.
They're sleeping.
No more stories.
Did you consider
why the demon does this?
To scare us, hmm?
For what benefit?
Chaos.
Distraction.
The devil
is the great deceiver.
He can make you see things
from your past.
Apparitions, memories,
always trying to deceive us.
So we never know
what he's thinking,
what he's planning.
If you do not believe me,
just ask my friend.
Come, I'll show you
what I found.
Amorth!
I noticed this
when I first arrived.
What is this?
You recognize this?
Yes, it's the seal
of the Spanish Inquisition.
Sì. The darkest time
in the history of the Church.
And they are...?
The victims.
The ones
who would not convert.
There is something
underneath this place.
Something is hidden here.
Come.
Hold this.
Two crossed keys.
Do you recognize this?
It's the Vatican Seal.
Sì, sì.
Is it gas?
A little gas. A little sulfur.
A little death.
So, no smoking, huh?
Stand back.
It's a door.
Push with me.
Okay.
Catacomb.
This is how they would bury
the dead.
I understand the Vatican
sealing this place off.
But why would they
leave someone?
The ring of
the Cardinal Protector.
He was the final hope.
The last protector.
It looks like he is a prisoner,
but he is not.
The cage is for his own safety.
They do this
when an exorcism fails.
To protect against
the demons escaped,
to trap something
they need to remain hidden.
Tomás, see if you
can open this gate.
It's locked.
Then our friend here
must have a key.
Where did you hide your key?
In the stomach.
Forgive me.
Try this.
Huh?
Come.
Gabriele. Gabriele.
It worked.
Ah.
Thank you, my friend.
Amy?
The gases and the sulfur,
it's getting stronger.
We are getting closer
to Hell.
Cardinal Sullivan,
is he all right?
- He collapsed.
- Holy Father.
Tell him.
Tell who?
Gabriele.
Gabriele?
Sì.
Amorth?
What trouble has he
got us into this time?
The Friar de Ojeda.
One of the greatest exorcists
of all time.
The seal of
the Spanish Inquisition.
His journal.
"Today, I was summoned
to the town of Segovia."
A possessed monk.
"In the year of our Lord
1475..."
"...while questioning the demon
possessing the monk,
"he answered me
from the mouth of another.
And then a third."
Multiple possessions.
It's a powerful demon.
Sì.
Amy?
The exorcist becomes
possessed himself.
Friar de Ojeda?
You know he is the man
who convinced Queen Isabella
of the need for an Inquisition.
So that means, from the time
he is possessed in 1475,
everything that happens
after this...
...is the work of the devil.
Centuries of persecution
and torture,
the worst abuses
of the Inquisition,
all started by the friar,
and done in the name of God...
by the devil.
The Vatican must have
known this.
The Church covered it up,
and they buried the truth here.
"Your sins
will seek you out."
The construction work
must have freed the demon.
Amy?
Henry.
It's okay, Mommy.
Henry's okay.
Oh, that's great.
Listen, Amy, why don't you
come downstairs with me?
I'm sorry, Mom.
I don't know what got into me.
Well, that's okay.
That's okay. I just...
I just need your sister
for a minute. Amy...
Can you forgive me, Mom?
"The great dragon
was hurled down.
Hurled into the earth,
where he was bound."
"And his angels with him."
Revelations.
200 rogue angels
buried into the earth.
This abbey is one of
those godforsaken places.
This demon,
he was trying to find them.
To raise an army
and destroy the Church.
Amy, come here.
What's in your hand, Mommy?
Amy, come here right now.
What's in your hand, Mommy?!
Look.
Watch me, Mommy.
Watch me.
His name...
the king of Hell.
Asmodeus.
Quickly!
Amy, use the sedative.
Tie his arms.
We have his name.
"Bring me the priest."
What did you say?
Those were the first words
the demon said.
"Bring me the priest."
It didn't mean me.
It wants you.
This demon feeds on exorcists.
He had a plan once.
To lure the friar here...
...hide amongst the righteous
and commit heinous acts
in the name of God.
It wants to do
the same thing again.
Using me to infiltrate
the Church.
What greater victory
for the devil...
than to claim the soul
of the Pope's exorcist.
Maybe, but we know
his name now.
So we have what we need
to beat it
and to save the child.
The only thing that can
defeat us is ourselves.
He will use your sins
against you.
I need to make confession.
To me?
You are a priest,
are you not?
Forgive me, Father,
for I have sinned.
Trust in the Lord.
I want to talk to you
about things
I have confessed before,
but they still burden me.
In 1942,
during the war,
I joined the Resistance.
I became a partisan and
I fought against the fascists.
So many of my friends
would die to German bullets.
Why them and not me?
Their dead bodies
would talk to me in my dreams.
To die in a war is heroic.
To survive a war... complex.
And then I begin to see
that my life had been spared.
It was my responsibility
to give it purpose.
And in my case,
that meant to serve God.
In all of my years,
I have tried to embrace
what is said in Matthew.
"What you do
for the least among you,
you do for me."
But when it mattered...
I failed.
I did not help her,
I did not believe her.
I did not listen.
Rosaria?
Sì.
Rosaria.
At night,
the devil fucks me.
What does this devil look like?
You.
She was not possessed.
She was mentally disturbed.
So I let someone else
handle her case.
Again, my pride.
I was an exorcist.
The mentally disturbed,
it's not my job.
Do you believe me now?
But that all changed
because of her.
To hear after her death
the rumors of the sexual abuse,
the cover-up
within the walls
of the Vatican City.
That innocent girl.
I did not help her
when she needed me.
Her soul is my burden.
And this demon, he knows that.
I know you
as a humble man of God,
Father Amorth.
It's time to lay down
that burden.
Forgive me, Father.
I absolve you of your sins
in the name of the Father,
of the Son
and of the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
I give you
the Miraculous Medal.
Holy fire insurance.
Very powerful.
To defeat
the king of Hell,
we require
the armor of God.
To defeat the king of Hell,
we require
the armor of God.
Remember, the demon will use
your sense against you.
Do not believe everything
you see or hear.
We have work to do.
We must save this child.
All done confessing?
Padre.
Did he bare his soul
to you, Tomás?
Like your little whore
bared her breasts?
Ignore it.
Pray for Henry.
No amount of prayers
can save Henry.
Let me in, Gabriele.
You know what I want.
Our Father...
who art in Heaven,
hallowed be thy name...
Was there really any point
confessing to your god, Gabe?
Give us this day
our daily bread...
Shouldn't you be confessing
to her?
You... are not there.
You are only in my mind.
I burn in Hell because of you!
You are not there.
You are only in my mind.
Father.
Join us in Hell, Gabe.
Take me in.
Don't you want me, Tomás?
Tell me to get on my knees
and say my prayers.
Fuck me, Tomás.
Deceiver.
Fuck me, Tomás!
Deceiver!
Fuck me, priest.
Oh, God.
Tomás, focus on the prayer.
Asmodeus!
Asmodeus, king of Gehenna,
this is the Cross of the Lord!
Release this child
and flee from the light of God!
See thee beneath God!
Never! Get out!
Get out of my house!
This is the house of God!
Not without my son!
Your son is gone!
His soul burns
and rots in Hell.
Admit to thy name, Asmodeus!
Never!
And bow to the power
of God Almighty!
Take me in, Gabe!
Oh, Mary,
Most High Queen of Heaven...
The Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou among...
...and of the Angels,
- and Mother of God...
- I am king!
You are under my dominion!
We humbly beseech you...
And here you will remain,
damned forever!
...the power and the mission...
...now and at the hour
of our death.
To crush Satan's skull!
I am Asmodeus,
king of Hell,
and I command you!
We beseech thee
to send thy holy angels...
...that under thy command
and by thy power, they may
pursue the evil spirits,
encounter them on every side,
resist their bold attacks,
and drive them hence
into the abyss of woe!
Mommy?
Mom, help me.
Speak to him, Julia.
Speak to him.
A mother's love never fails.
Henry! Henry, I love you.
Call to him.
Henry, come back to me.
Henry, please talk to me.
Mommy, they're hurting me.
Oh, God.
Henry, we need your help.
You must resist.
I can't.
Mom?
Henry.
What's happening?
Oh, my God.
Holy shit.
The omnipotent.
It's in them both.
Amy.
Give me what I want!
No!
Surrender yourself to me!
Julia!
I told you, bitch.
You're all gonna die!
Amy, please.
Amy's gone.
Julia, resist!
Don't lose faith!
Give me back my children!
Your children are gone!
Please. Amy, please.
I love you.
- It's me you want.
- Let the children go.
They all suffer because of you.
Say the words, piggy.
Be the martyr
you dreamed of being.
Be my piggy.
Take me.
Mom.
No! Gabriele!
Father.
Mommy?
What have you done?
Take the cross from my hand.
Okay. Okay.
Take it.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
It's okay.
Oh, my God.
Henry, you came back to me.
You're safe now.
Take it!
Get them out of here.
Yes.
Go!
Hey. Hey.
Julia, we have to go.
Please, let's go.
Put your arms around me.
Come on, run. Amy, come on.
Your soul is mine.
Sullivan.
Sullivan!
I knew you would
sacrifice yourself
to save those children,
and now you are mine.
Come on. Hurry.
The boy, he's safe now.
Just get away from here.
Go.
Thank you, Father.
I need my pig, Gabe.
You will not take me.
You will not take me!
You prideful fool.
The friar said
the exact same thing.
Forgive me, Lord.
Not yet.
I need my pig to get me
inside the Vatican, Gabe.
Gabriele!
Damn us both to Hell.
You're too late, Tomás.
He's gone, your friend.
Gone.
So...
...run along.
It would be my great pleasure
to excoriate your soul
and eviscerate your memory.
Gabriele, listen to me.
Fight it.
It is just in your head.
We can only be defeated
by ourselves.
He is not here!
The little piggy
is slopping at Hell's trough,
where he belongs.
I know you're here, Gabriele.
Pray with me!
God is not here!
God is always in our hearts.
Focus on the prayer.
Where two of you gather...
in my name,
there am I.
Lord, have mercy.
Say it! Lord, have mercy!
God is with you,
Gabriele.
Find him.
Finish it, Tomás.
Finish it.
Give up. He is mine.
I adjure you,
in the name
of the spotless lamb.
The word made flesh
commands you.
Asmodeus!
Jesus of Nazareth commands you!
And now I adjure you
in his name!
Lord, heed my prayer! Say it!
No!
- Gabriele.
- We're not done yet.
You're coming to Hell, priests.
I will take you both.
Adella.
Your sins will seek...
Seek you out.
Tomás, use the medal!
Lord, grant me the power!
Gabriele!
Asmodeus! In the name
of the Holy Mother!
See thee beneath God.
See thee beneath God!
Tomás, pray the final rites.
In the name of the Father...
...and of the Son
and of the Holy Spirit,
see thee beneath God!
Gabriele, are you okay?
Not so bad.
Tomás.
What?
You look like shit.
Eh.
Bless you, Tomás.
You learned the Latin.
Yes, it's similar
to the Spanish.
Very similar to the Spanish.
You know, the God,
he works in very
mysterious ways.
For you.
Yes, he does.
Cuckoo.
Is that you, Gabriele?
And I have brought
Padre Esquibel to meet you.
You look well, Your Holiness.
Thanks to you both.
I'm glad to see you.
You had me worried this time.
Sounded dangerous.
Sometimes you fly
a little too close to the sun.
It has not
killed me yet.
The Church will not forget
what you have done.
You struck a mighty blow
for our side.
Saint Michael would be proud.
Grazie.
And this is why God
put you here, Gabriele.
And God has made a good choice
in you, too, Father Esquibel.
Thank you, Holy Father.
The congregation has requested
a full report on Spain.
A full report.
So Cardinale Sullivan
can tell me again
that evil only exists
in my imagination?
You haven't heard?
Cardinal Sullivan has taken
a sabbatical
in the Isle of Guam.
I shall pray...
for Guam.
And who has, uh,
filled his shoes?
I have found someone
far more trustworthy.
I will leave you
in his good hands.
See thee beneath God.
Welcome to the holiest
of holies.
12 centuries of treasures.
Letters from saints
and apostles.
Books of wisdom and piety.
Revelations of the spirit.
The entire canon
of Christian thought.
The Vatican has purchased the
abbey from the Vasquez family
and reconsecrated the soil.
The family has safely
relocated back to the U.S.,
where the boy made
a full recovery.
Hmm.
The friar's diary
is proving very useful
despite his abhorrence.
Asmodeus has been defeated,
but there are many more
to be found.
Soon, we will know
all of the other
199 sites on Earth
where God is not welcome.
Gabriele,
will you take on this task?
This would be more than a
lifetime's work for one priest.
But two priests...
What do you think, Tomás?
Can you see this now
as a calling?
And that we must serve God
the way he wants us
to serve him?
Let's go to work.
Let's go to Hell.